<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io</id>
    <title>Light Up My Nights</title>
    <updated>2026-01-18T06:40:43.835Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Speak for the misunderstood</subtitle>
    <logo>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2026, Light Up My Nights</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Boardmasters 2024: Wunderhorse avoid rain to talk main stage debut, a second album and getting their surf on]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/banbury-guardian-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/banbury-guardian-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-18T06:24:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Banbury Guardian</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Banbury Guardian</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Banbury Guardian
作者：Patrick Hollis
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>A four piece who formed from a solo project of lead singer Jacob Slater, Wunderhorse have blossomed in the years following the Covid-19 lockdown. On a misty day on the Cornish coast, the band made another piece of personal history.</p>
<p>Wunderhorse made their Boardmasters debut last year, but made their first appearance on the main stage this time around. Ahead of the show, the band who is Jacob Slater (Vocals), Harry Tristan Fowler (Guitar), Pete Woodin (Bass) and Jamie Staples (Drums)  chatted to NationalWorld about how they are finding things at the moment.</p>
<p>Jacob, who lives in Newquay and has had the festival on his doorstep for several years, said: “I think we’re ready for the bigger stage, it is raining though so I hope some people turn up.</p>
<p>“Festivals are a bit more touch and go really. Mainly because you don’t get a sound check, you have to sometimes affect the kind of chaos that comes with it. You’ve just got to make peace with it really. On this Pete added the interesting line of “always hope for the worst,” as a way of expecting the unexpected.</p>
<p>Wunderhorse have their new album coming out later this month. They explained some of the process of this, and why due to the first album being a lot of Jacob’s work, it feels like the band’s first.</p>
<p>Jamie said:  “This felt in a way like our debut album as a band. It’s like this is our first ever Wunderhorse record as a complete unit.</p>
<p>Jacob added: “The first album was mainly me writing it, it was a totally different playing field. Once we found the world a bit, it all flowed quite easily. Most of this record was written in the studio, which isn’t what we had planned.</p>
<p>“It was an exercise of how to do things. We got bored with how the record was going to sound, and that was new to us.”</p>
<p>With the band looking to explore after their set, Harry said: “We’re going to have a wander around in a bit, but we just got here. The show is always the focus and then after that we’ll see if we have time.</p>
<p>Jacob added: “I’ll be surfing tomorrow, I take every opportunity I get to surf,” with the acknowledgment of how close several of Cornwall’s beaches are to the festival site.</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.banburyguardian.co.uk/culture/music/music-festival-boardmasters-shows-cornwall-4737192" title="10.08.24">Boardmasters 2024: Wunderhorse avoid rain to talk main stage debut, a second album and getting their surf on</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse Are Riding A Nice Wave]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/northern-transmissions-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/northern-transmissions-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-18T06:09:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Northern Transmissions</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Northern Transmissions</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Northern Transmissions
作者：Ethan Rebalkin
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>Wunderhorse have amassed a devoted fan base through their post-punk expertise and an undeniable live show that has seen them tour across Europe, even opening up for indie-giants Fontaines D.C. Prior to the release of their much anticipated sophomore effort Midas, singer-songwriter Jacob Slater joined Northern Transmissions to discuss Midas’ mission statement, and his approach to remaining grounded in the midst of an unpredictable musical landscape.</p>
<p><strong>Northern Transmissions: A big focus for this record was to have an unpolished recording approach. Was your writing process for the record something that was equally as carefree, or did that part have more of a considered approach?</strong></p>
<p>Jacob Slater: It’s a funny one really. We went in with a handful of ideas which quickly became apparent that most of them weren’t going to work – so there was a brief moment of panic. I dredged up a sequence of chords that I had been messing around with and that was the idea that turned into “Midas.” We wrote that on the spot in the studio. From then, we wrote most of the record that way, in the studio while we were there. I don’t know how or why it worked but for that month we were in the studio most of the record just came together on the spot.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Even the lyrics came together on the spot?</strong></p>
<p>JS: Yeah the only two songs that made it onto the record which were written prior to the recording was “Arizona” and “Superman.” Other then that, everything was done in the session. Basically, 3 weeks in there, a month of touring then went back in. Everything is from that period.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Did you feel like even if you didn’t have any fully-realized musical ideas, that you had an overall mission statement or any particular themes you wanted to write about for the record?</strong></p>
<p>JS: I think the main thing we were focusing on going into it was the sound of it. Just making sure that it was more rough around the edges compared to the first one. Y’know we’re such a live-band and that side of us wasn’t really reflected in the first album. So that was the main mission really. Looking back on the Midas sessions, themes lyrically and stuff came to light. It was all such a small bracket of time that it was all drawing from the same emotional place.</p>
<p><strong>NT: You’ve mentioned that you got really really burnt out from your first band Dead Pretties. Is there anything now that you’re trying to do to avoid burnout like that?</strong></p>
<p>JS: Surfing was a big thing for me. I’ve been surfing since I was a kid so I went back to that during that period. I still do that whenever I can, but it can be difficult as the schedule starts filling up more and more. I’m not doing much of the things I was doing when I was younger on a regular basis. I guess you have to implement that a bit if you want to keep going. Our band has to tour more and more, because that’s the main way we make money because income from streaming doesn’t really cut it. If you’re looking at your year, and got 10-11 months of touring, you’ve gotta look at that and say well, you can’t have fun all the time. Which is wise, I guess.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Did it feel daunting re-entering the musical landscape after already taking a crack at it with another band?</strong></p>
<p>JS: Yeah, I think I just said “oh well I’ll just do something new.” But it took years and years to get that off the ground, it was quite a bit harder the second time around. That first band, I mean we never blew-up or anything but it looked promising. We got in when we were 17-18, and there was a lot of stuff happening in South-London. There was this scene that was being written about a lot and when I came back with the Wunderhorse stuff, it had just disappeared. I was drifting around, wondering if anyone gave a shit about it. Luckily some of the Fontaines D.C. boys heard the music and asked us to open up for them, and that was when the ball started to really roll for us, when people started seeing us live.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Was it a challenge to shed any sort of identity that you or the audience had attached to yourself through your old projects?</strong></p>
<p>JS: Yeah I think whenever it’s something new people might take an interest through the old thing. They expect a certain thing from you and maybe they get upset that you aren’t what they thought you were and go off and listen to something else. Which is fine, that’s to be expected.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Is a small, local scene something that is still important to you or is that something you think is more important as you’re starting out?</strong></p>
<p>JS: I think it’s more important maybe at the beginning, and more exciting. Especially when you’re younger. I just try to focus on what I’m doing now, and not let what other people are doing influence me or seep into my subconscious. I don’t want to do that, and don’t want to get into a position where I’m doing that. Best to just stay in your own lane sometimes.</p>
<p><strong>NT: What do you find is the most distracting for you now?</strong></p>
<p>JS: Just wanting to go surfing all the time. Especially when you’re tired on tour. I just think I wanna go to South-America and surf for a year. But I reckon I’d get a month into it and just wanna get back to the music.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Is that kind of why you came back to the music in the first place?</strong></p>
<p>Slater: Yeah definitely. It felt like I had something to do that I hadn’t done yet.</p>
<p><strong>NT: Jacob, how excited are you that Oasis have reunited?</strong></p>
<p>Slater: Yeah! I definitely would like to see them. Everyone has been waiting for a while. As a kid, I went through that period of listening to many of the first albums. Especially Definitely Maybe was the one I thought had the stones on it. The music definitely carried some weight. I think I was about 13 or 14 when I first heard that, and it made an impact. I would love to see them do some of the stuff from that and who knows, maybe even a support slot?</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://northerntransmissions.com/wunderhorse-are-riding-a-nice-wave/" title="31.08.24">Wunderhorse Are Riding A Nice Wave</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse: “I think there’s a charm to sounding a bit scruffy”]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/hendicott-writing-interview-2/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/hendicott-writing-interview-2/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-18T05:10:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with James Hendicott.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with James Hendicott.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Hendicott Writing
作者：James Hendicott
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>When Wunderhorse first dropped in on Dublin, it was to immediate acclaim. With a cutting guitar vibe and tracks that see them explore love, loss and a sense of eerie distortion of reality, Jacob Slater’s band were the unheralded support act for Fontaines DC when they played the Iveagh Gardens a couple of summers back, at the time the band’s largest show.</p>
<p>That show has proven a platform here: Wunderhorse now headline Vicar Street themselves, with sophomore album ‘Midas’ widely acclaimed as one of the best guitar albums of 2024 so far. On it, Wunderhorse became a band, as opposed to the previous ‘Slater and friends’ type set up.</p>
<p>“‘Cub’ [the debut album] seemed to steadily grow, so we’re hoping for the same thing with ‘Midas’. It does feel like it’s all heading in the right direction,” Slater says. “There’s a natural chemistry now to the way we play together, and Wunderhorse has become a lot bigger and better than me on my own. It makes sense that it’s a band. I’m still writing the bones of the songs, the chords and the lyrics, but Jamie on drums, Pete on bass and Harry on guitar all write their own parts, rather than my old place as a kind of musical director.”</p>
<p>“Most of the tunes on ‘Midas’ we recorded on the first couple of takes, which is how we wanted it. The things I like about guitar music, rock music, has been lost to this modern idea of chasing perfection. A lot of my favourite records sound a bit scruffy in places. I think there’s a charm to that.”</p>
<p>“I listen to tracks back and notice mistakes, and that’s part of it, but it is what it is. The band is forged out of playing live, and we wanted the record to be ‘warts and all’, a representation of that side of us. A lot of people got into us from coming to see the live gig, so we wanted to give a bit of that.”</p>
<p>“Recording in Minnesota came from Craig, our producer. We told him the kind of record we wanted to make, and he picked out the studio based on that. The place in Minnesota was near the top of his list. I thought it was a surreal thing that would never happen, but it did.”</p>
<p>“We feel quite blessed. Of course there are some hurdles, and some illusions are shattered. You do lose that naivety, and I realised that most people in the industry might have a different motive to what you think at the start. You get wise to it. Our position is very good, the label very supportive. It’s night and day from some of our situations in the past.”</p>
<p>“With my last band, Dead Pretties, we weren’t prepared for a big record contract. It all went wrong, which was nobody’s fault but ours. The wheels came off a lot quicker than I thought they would.”</p>
<p>“Now, we played Kentish Town Forum, selling it out, which was great, and we packed the Woodsies Stage at Glastonbury, which was a real shock. I wasn’t expecting many to come and see us. At the other end of it, you start to go a bit loopy when you tour the States. It’s like driving around in this tin box watching the world go by across a whole continent.”</p>
<p>Wunderhorse will see ever more of that world, with newly launched ‘Midas’ already taking off, and looking likely to propel them into the upper echelons of the growing dingy-rock scene. Their Vicar Street show on October 16th will feel, to Irish fans, like a euphoric return.</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.hendicottwriting.com/2025/01/wunderhorse-i-think-theres-a-charm-to-sounding-a-bit-scruffy/" title="08.01.25">Wunderhorse: “I think there’s a charm to sounding a bit scruffy”</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse: “I hope to avoid being trapped in a style”]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/hendicott-writing-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/hendicott-writing-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-18T05:04:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with James Hnedicott.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with James Hnedicott.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Hendicott Writing
作者：James Hendicott
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>Jacob Slater, frontman of powerful new indie-rock band Wunderhorse, has form. A few years ago, as the vocalist in garage rock band The Dead Pretties, Slater was briefly the talk of the London indie scene, his band releasing just a handful of singles but garnering a massive cult following over the course of a few months. That band burnt out and called it a day before true fame hit.</p>
<p>Slater’s return as Wunderhorse has been helped no little by Dublin legends Fontaines DC, who have been bringing the laid back, Cornwall-based surfer dude and his band around with them on their sell out tours. As Wunderhorse, Slater is still building a series of guitar-heavy but emotionally-led tracks, in between a life which he spends heavily on his other passion, riding waves.</p>
<p>In fact, when we catch up with him, he’s sat in a cafe in Cornwall, as his own home is a surf hang out without a reliable internet connection. “There’s crossover between surf culture and music,” he says. “A lot of people down here play music, either professionally or for fun. I guess both are considered more left field pursuits, so it makes sense.”</p>
<p>As for those early days with Dead Pretties: “I was playing music for very different reasons, Slater explains. “It was all about making it big, going as crazy on stage as possible, big songs. By the time I turned 20 I was quite burnt out, to be honest. As well as the punky kind of stuff I’d always listened to softer stuff, too. More varied classics. When that band finished, I wanted my next band to be more varied, not to make me feel so trapped in a style.”</p>
<p>“I guess it’s a common problem for lots of artists that they establish themselves with an album with a specific style and get trapped in that style. I hope if I avoid that from the beginning, I won’t lose too many listeners when I keep producing varied stuff.”</p>
<p>“When I got signed, during covid, the group I was playing with was a loose line up,” he continues. “The label wanted to sign me as a solo artist, but I’ve been playing with a much more solidified kind of group of people, so it’s more like a band. That’s how it is now.”</p>
<p>“The record was recorded ages ago but Covid has screwed everyone up.”</p>
<p>The debut album from Wunderhorse is called ‘Cub’, and seems to draw influences from sounds as diverse as Neil Young and The Libertines. Slater, though, has an unlikely side gig, too – he played Sex Pistols drummer Paul Cook in the Disney movie about the band, entitled ‘Pistol’ – a sbow of divertsity, given he usually performs on guitar and vocals.</p>
<p>“It was definitely a bit of a change of scene to be behind the kit, but I loved it,” Slater says. “I like to get out of my comfort zone. If something came up I’d definitely carry on with it.”</p>
<p>“It’s nice to be back talking about the album though,” he says. “I’m not getting my hopes up about it, the reward for me is actually doing an album. Obviously like any artist I hope as many people hear it as possible, but I’m not going to be brokenhearted if it’s not a big, successful thing.”</p>
<p>“What was great about the Fontaines DC support slots was that Grian Chattan had heard of us through friends, and he just gave us a call,” he continues. “It was done through a mutual respect, one musician to another, rather than a clinical industry thing. That meant something to us.”</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.hendicottwriting.com/2022/11/wunderhorse-i-hope-to-avoid-being-trapped-in-a-style/" title="30.11.22">Wunderhorse: “I hope to avoid being trapped in a style”</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】WONDERLAND MEETS: WUNDERHORSE]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/wonderland-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/wonderland-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T13:16:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Wonderland meet the band revitalising British guitar music in the depths of central London. Preparing to unleash their sophomore record Midas, they reveal a sprawling and spirited journey that has left them ambitious, angry, and united.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Wonderland meet the band revitalising British guitar music in the depths of central London. Preparing to unleash their sophomore record Midas, they reveal a sprawling and spirited journey that has left them ambitious, angry, and united.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Wonderland
作者：Ben Tibbits
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>I’m huddled over a table in an old school Soho boozer, with half drunk Guinness’ and baccy dust littering the table, scrummaging for a headline from a band far too savvy to bestow it. The act in question, Wunderhorse, have “no idea” if they are leading the charge of a British guitar music renaissance, a query I’ve dangled in front of them. Given their humility, I guess it’s down to me to make such an argument.</p>
<p>Over the past decade or two, there has been a systemic shift in the industry and wider society that makes it near impossible for a band to capture the imagination of listeners that they may have, without pretence, in earlier eras. Jacob Slater, UK four-piece Wunderhose’s frontman – witty, chiselled, moral – breaks down the change in no uncertain terms. “With bands like the Libertines and the Strokes, there was something about what they were doing that seemed attractive because it was outlaw-ish,” he begins, the band murmuring in agreement. “Which is something that young people have always been drawn to, whether they are holding a guitar or riding a horse like a cowboy. It’s that spirit of living on the fringe. But nowadays it’s hard to retain that sense of mystery because of stuff like social media. It’s like – ‘here we are behind the scenes, here’s this person eating their fucking dinner’. You don’t want that. If you’re a kid and you hear a song that takes your breath away and your mind to beautiful things, you don’t want to be told that that person is just like you. You want to believe that there’s something else out there, something beyond your fucking suburban town. That’s what captured my attention when I was younger, and there isn’t really that much of that anymore.”</p>
<p>Slater’s words, for me, bring a certain degree of irony, as it was his own music that captivated me in the manner he describes, a rare anomaly in my listening norm given the over-saturation and lack of earnestness in much of this TikTokian era of consumption. But when I first heard “Teal”, the 2021 debut single from Wunderhorse which was at that point the solo moniker of Slater, emotion gushed all over me, drowning me in sentiment. It was a symbolic moment, a sonic vehicle of inner sanctimony, and a cry for clarity within my own personal whirlwind of feeling.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768483232477.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>“I don’t think there was much thought behind why [“Teal” was the debut release]. We just thought it was a strong song and wanted to get it out,” the song’s writer shrugs casually, rationalising the impact of the track. His band, though, clearly feel the unique and boundless effervescence of the cut, not unlike myself. “It just had that more visceral energy,” bassist Pete Woodin offers. “Nothing needed to be overcomplicated on that song,” Jamie Staples, the drummer, adds. “I remember the first time I heard Jacob play it, I won’t forget that.”</p>
<p>The bond between the four twenty-somethings is light-hearted, focused, and without ego. The seasoned musicians have known and played with each other to differing degrees for years, with inter-collaborative relationships carved out pre-Wunderhorse’s inception. To call them an ‘indie’ band – as they are regularly coined – is unjust, and guitarist Harry Tristan Fowler doesn’t like it much. “I always get weird about indie,” he winces. “I don’t feel like an indie band and I don’t know what one is anymore.” Wunderhorse isn’t a concept to box in, after all. There’s a timelessness and fluidity to their sound and methodology that is rare to uncover. The aforementioned “Teal” for instance, could be plucked from a myriad of decades, with its raw 70s edge down to its anthemic late 90s-tinged climax. “We all listen to stuff from different times, reaching into the past,” Slater shares. “I think that’s what naturally comes out when we write.”</p>
<p>The band’s apexian figure has been on a topsy-turvy musical journey of his own to get to this point. Slater first announced himself to the industry as the singer of Dead Pretties, the punk rock trio who became notorious for their raucous live shows and anarchic presence. “I definitely learnt a lot about what not to do,” he reflects on his time with the Pretties. “Having said that, we did have a very good work ethic; when we were trying to get signed we were playing multiple nights a week every week, sacrificing everything to do it. That was carried forward; I didn’t go into the industry knowing anyone or having any sort of leg up, it was just getting out there and doing the hard yards.”</p>
<p>Although undoubtedly a hotly-tipped rising act within the constraints of a postured punk scene, after a period of murky occurrences Slater emerged from his former band, feeling it wasn’t an “appropriate vehicle to reflect the breadth of my influences,” he pinpoints. “It was too narrow an avenue of expression for all the stuff I wanted to do. And also it had become a lot about the other stuff, and less to do with the music, which was just getting in the way of creative impulse.” For Slater, Wunderhorse is what rose from the ashes of Pretties; a solo endeavour, backed for gigs and recording by three session musicians who had their own ventures outside of the project.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768483251831.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>After a smattering of singles across ’21 and the first half of the following year, Slater shared his debut album, Cub, in October of 2022 — a raw, rousing and stylistically sprawling opening body of work. Although the album was hotly-anticipated by many, there wasn’t an overt expectation attached to the project, absent somewhat from the “toxic blight on a generation” social media and its wheel of discovery. “I didn’t know what to expect,” he says. “There were plenty of… [trails away in thought] put it this way — nobody was telling me it was going to do well. Not in a negative way, it was more about managing expectations.”</p>
<p>Rather than get too involved with online rigamarole, the record instead relied on word of mouth and a community of musicians to bolster its popularity. “A lot of its success actually came from other musicians picking up on the songs and asking if we wanted to come on tour. That exposed us to much bigger crowds and different demographics. The industry had very little to do with it, with the exception of radio where we had some good plugins. So a lot came from our peers, which is good, it felt right. It restored some faith in what we were doing and that it had merit, because these are people who we respect for what they are doing as well.”</p>
<p>Such musicians who picked up on Wunderhorse’s boundless potential include Irish troubadours Fontaines D.C. and legacy crooners The Pixies, both of whom invited Slater and co to open for them on their respective tours. Promptly graduating from dingy pubs to iconic venues brimming with spectators there broadly to see the following act, these elongated periods of touring were a learning curve and a much needed baptism of fire for the band. “When we first started out on the Fontaines tour we were playing in tiny rooms ourselves at our own gigs,” Woodin says. “Then suddenly we were playing on stage in front of thousands of people who have no idea who you are. We were like — ‘right, let’s put fucking everything into this’. And that’s been the ethos that we’ve had ever since.”</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768483282421.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>During this period, with the joy and strain of tour life, the four boys grew tighter, and Wunderhorse transitioned from a solo moniker into a four piece act. “I like feeling like I’m part of something that’s bigger than me,” Slater explains. “The nature of us touring together, we started getting really closely knit. After Harry joined, we elevated our live show and there was this feeling that it gave us, and we took that feeling into the next process of writing a record. There’s a lot of things about Midas that wouldn’t be as good if it was left up to me. There’s a lot of intrinsic human elements to the playing of each person that make it what it is. I couldn’t have come up with that in my own head, it had to come from this group of individuals.”</p>
<p>Wunderhorse’s ‘sophomore’ album, Midas, is set for release on 30th August, of which at the time of writing a trio of teasers have arrived – “July”, “Silver”, and the title track. In many ways the record feels like a debut, given the circumstances around the strengthening of the band’s agenda. Unlike Cub, they approached the album’s writing collectively, and devised it quickly, within a month or so. They sought after an upper echelon producer in Craig Silvey (a Grammy-winner for his work with Arcade Fire) to meet a self-formed deadline designed to push them in their artistic and aspirational capabilities. “I just lied to everyone who was funding it and said that I’d written the record,” Slater jokes on the swift turnaround. “Luckily, the alchemy of the whole thing made some good brew.”</p>
<p>What boiled from the short sharp burst of writing and recording is a mortar of magnificence. Midas is a potent listen; sometimes fierce and angry, other times poignant and delicate, it showcases a fully-fledged, multi-dimensional artistry, never outstaying its welcome, even with tracks like the closer clocking in at nearly nine minutes. Midas moulds the grandly-scoped cinema of early 70s Rolling Stones and the broad but barring songwriting of Bob Dylan with the raw, rousing ambience of Nirvana and The Pixies and instinctive existentialism of PJ Harvey and Thom Yorke. It’s a homage to the past but never derivative, with a crisp vitality to the production. It is amongst the British guitar records of the year, and a rallying cry to an industry that has in large lost faith in four white lads holding instruments. After all, Wunderhorse are “a kicking and scratching band,” Slater self-defines. “Some bands – they might be great bands or they might be shit bands – get big really quick. We’ve been doing this a while, way before anyone even knew who we were. And it’s always been that thing of – we’re going to get over here. If we’ve got to go the long way to do that, that’s fine with us. It makes us who we are, you know?”</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768483307118.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>With Midas’ late August release set to up the ante tenfold, the band will play some of the biggest shows of their career before 2024 is done. A run of summer festivals, including a favourable Reading &amp; Leeds spot, will be ensued by an October headline UK tour (an O2 Academy Brixton extravaganza nestled amidst) and then a stint of shows once again supporting their friends in Fontaines D.C.. Then? “Fuck knows. If there’s songs, we’ll write a record.” And if there isn’t – if the white noise becomes too much for a band built on their love for the sound and a lack of entertainment at the notion of fame – there’s always surfing, for Slater at least.</p>
<p>“Just before Covid I moved down to Cornwall because I’ve always wanted to live there, and I was in-between projects – Wunderhorse hadn’t really got going yet,” Slater says. “I lost a lot of faith – not in music, but in the world that surrounded music, the industry. I felt like I needed to get my head together a little bit and I had mates down there. It was just a door opening into another world that had nothing to do with music. It showed me how much bigger life is than music. It’s very easy to be consumed by music, and that’s a beautiful thing – until it’s not, then it can be quite limiting. And you need things to feed the creative machine, and if you stay in the same place for too long, it starts to eat itself. [Surfing] just feels great. Once you persevere it and get past a certain point with it, that feeling it gives you is indescribable. It’s almost a threat to my musical career, sometimes I’m like, ‘fuck it, I’m just going to go and surf and never come back.’ It’s dangerous.”</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.wonderlandmagazine.com/2024/07/25/wonderland-meets-wunderhorse/" title="25.07.24">WONDERLAND MEETS: WUNDERHORSE</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse: Jacob Slater's journey from Cornwall surf instructor to the next big rock star]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/cornwalllive-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/cornwalllive-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T12:42:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Newquay's Jacob Slater has celebrity fans in Sam Fender and Fontaines DC, and played a Sex Pistol on TV</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Newquay's Jacob Slater has celebrity fans in Sam Fender and Fontaines DC, and played a Sex Pistol on TV</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：CornwallLive
作者：Lee Trewhela
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>Jacob Slater has been tipped as the next Sam Fender, has had his band's debut album mentioned as one of the best of 2022 and is currently on a UK tour supporting Irish wonders Fontaines DC. Not bad for a bloke who was teaching surfing in Newquay until recently.</p>
<p>Jacob fronts and is the songwriter for Wunderhorse, whose album Cub is a brilliant catalogue of teenage life - ill-fated love, drugs, self-destruction, depression as well as youthful joy - all to a rousing soundtrack that harks back to the 1990s, with touches of Nirvana, Elliott Smith, Radiohead, Jeff Buckley and, on the epic Poppy, Stone Roses at their most majestic. It is a thing of wonder.</p>
<p>After a teenage Jacob - now 24 - called it a day on fronting the much-hyped but ultimately unsuccessful punk outfit Dead Pretties in 2017, he moved to Cornwall to take care of himself, indulge in his passion for surfing and live a less chaotic life. The clean coastal air and slower pace of life quickly paid dividends, allowing Jacob to grow as an artist and apply himself to building an introspective and thoughtful songbook, without losing any of the bite from his previous endeavour.</p>
<p>Speaking to CornwallLive from the band's tour bus en route to a gig in Glasgow, Jacob said: &quot;I still live in Cornwall but I'm basically never there. It's a real shame - I love touring but I also love surfing and I love my mates down there. It's a real blessing to be doing what I'm doing at the moment, so I guess it's part and parcel that you're always going to miss home.&quot;</p>
<p>The band will be ramping up their burgeoning success with a huge UK tour next year, which includes two dates in Cornwall, which means at least he'll get back home to Newquay for a few days in 2023. Wunderhorse also support Pixies on their European tour in February and March.</p>
<p>&quot;I started going down to Newquay when I was about nine years old. A guy called Matthew taught me to surf and I fell in love with the place and always wanted to live down there. About three and a half years ago I moved down permanently, but then all this kicked off so I'm not there that much at the moment.&quot;</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768481209055.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Jacob added: &quot;It was a safe haven and sanctuary when the Dead Pretties folded and still is totally. There's space and time to think in Cornwall. Being in London, it feels like the whole place is eating you alive - you can breathe a bit easier in Cornwall.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that some of the songs on Cub were written during the changeover period from London to Cornwall, but a batch of new songs are much more of a band effort. &quot;That record's just come out, but for me those songs are really old now. Lots of the stuff that will be on the next record will be songs that have been written on the road or in Cornwall.</p>
<p>&quot;I was lucky in that I met the rest of the guys in the band when I was living in London, before I moved to Cornwall. I spent five years living in London - I served my time. Each to their own, it's just not for me. When I came down to Cornwall I was actually teaching surfing - that's how I got on my feet and was paying the rent for a season, then I got really lucky and got this acting job.&quot;</p>
<p>That acting job was playing Sex Pistols drummer Paul Cook in Danny Boyle's acclaimed 2022 TV series, Pistol.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768481417953.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>He explained: &quot;Someone I knew from the music world reached out to say they were holding auditions and they thought I was the right age and look, and they were looking for musicians. I thought I'd give it a go, not expecting anything, and struck it super lucky.&quot;</p>
<p>People wrote off the series before it was even screened - including Johnny Rotten himself - but when it was aired it received glowing reviews. &quot;Everyone knew that would happen. If you're going to make a show about the Sex Pistols there's going to be a load of true fans going 'it's f<em><strong>ing s</strong></em>'. But it's really good and it was a lot of fun making it.&quot;</p>
<p>Jacob is seen on the show wearing Vivienne Westwood's infamous and controversial Cambridge Rapist T-shirt, which was often worn by the Pistols at the height of their infamy.</p>
<p>&quot;We were filming in Peckham Rye and I was walking down the road to get some cigarettes, and I was in costume, wearing that T-shirt. I was strolling to the shops and I was wondering why everyone was looking at me so weird. On my way back I suddenly realised emblazoned on the front of me were the words 'Cambridge Rapist' and so I started running back to the set, which probably made me look even more suspicious.&quot;</p>
<p>Conor Deegan, from Fontaines DC, made Cub his favourite album of the year in the new issue of Mojo magazine, saying: &quot;The act that really wowed me this year is Wunderhorse. We took them on tour to America and I got to watch them a lot. They're a great band, probably better than us. They brought it every night consistently.&quot;</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="3"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768481504596.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Jacob was not aware of the glowing recommendation and told the rest of the band, while I was on the phone to him: &quot;Wahey, good on him. That's news to us. I knew Grian (Chatten, singer with Fontaines DC) before everything started. He and a couple of the other members of the band came down to one of our shows at the Lexington and made it known they were fans of our music. We went to the States with them and now we're doing this tour with them. We're very happy to be part of their journey.</p>
<p>&quot;We're all glad that the album's been received well and getting some respect from the right kind of people. We do feel we're on the cusp of something but more within ourselves. We're really excited to see the promotion of this record through and then get the next one going. We all feel that we have so much more to offer musically.&quot;</p>
<p>I mentioned some of the artists Cub reminds me of and Jacob said they're all musicians he loves: &quot;There was a period when all me and my friend Harry, who's in the band, listened to was Jeff Buckley. These days, I'm much more into an Elliott Smith kind of vibe, some of the phrasing is very much inspired by him.&quot;</p>
<p>What about the epic Stone Roses-sounding ending to the song, Poppy? &quot;That's exactly what we were trying to do - how can we make the ending sound like I Am The Resurrection, that big jam session? I feel that people don't jam that much nowadays on album tracks and that celebration of how much fun music can be when you're all going hammer and tongs at it.&quot;</p>
<p>What does Jacob make of people saying he's the new Sam Fender, who Wunderhorse have also supported?</p>
<p>&quot;We know Sam and he's a lovely guy. It's cool to be compared to someone who's doing really well for themselves,&quot; he said. &quot;Personally, I think we sound quite different to him. I guess it's an obvious comparison to make as we both make uptempo guitar music - Sam's got his own thing going but so do we. It's nice to be compared, but we're definitely separate entities.&quot;</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="4"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768481569169.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Jacob told me: &quot;Playing in Newquay and Falmouth next year will be a blessing. Our tour manager helped build the inside of the Cornish Bank, so it will be good to play there.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to try to get a week or maybe two back in Newquay before Christmas. Next year's going to be so busy that I've managed to get a few weeks surfing in Morocco with my mate Matty, so that's going to be my holiday and then it will be straight back into gigging next year, which is full on to the end of the year. Recording the next album is on the cards too.&quot;</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.cornwalllive.com/whats-on/music-nightlife/wunderhorse-jacob-slaters-journey-cornwall-7835406" title="19.11.22">Wunderhorse: Jacob Slater's journey from Cornwall surf instructor to the next big rock star</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse: ‘We’ve kicked and scratched our way to this point’]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/prs-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/prs-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T12:24:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Ahead of their new album Midas, the four-piece discuss their work ethic, banding together as songwriters and ‘conquering the world’.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Ahead of their new album Midas, the four-piece discuss their work ethic, banding together as songwriters and ‘conquering the world’.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：PRS for music
作者：Rishi Shah
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>‘The minute you think you’ve found it and are going to stay there, you’re in serious trouble,’ Wunderhorse frontman Jacob Slater sagely tells M.</p>
<p>Having turned heads with their raw fusion of indie, punk and Americana on their 2022 debut LP Cub (which was written solely by Jacob), the band, who now operate as a four-piece, were determined to push into uncharted territory with their follow-up Midas, out tomorrow (30 August).</p>
<p>‘There's a Bob Dylan quote, “We have never arrived. We are in a constant state of becoming”,’ Jacob, reflecting on Wunderhorse’s evolving ethos, continues. ‘That’s fucking bang-on [from] the big man, the OG!’</p>
<p>Completed by guitarist Harry Fowler, drummer Jamie Staples and bassist Peter Woodin, the quartet broke new ground with Midas by writing collaboratively. A songwriting approach that was informed by their extensive time on tour together, Wunderhorse were intent on capturing their ‘visceral’ live energy on record that was somewhat absent from, as Jamie describes, the ‘safe’ recordings heard on Cub.</p>
<p>‘I want you to feel like you’re in a room full of teenagers thrashing out some songs,’ Jacob says about Midas. ‘We could have gone more commercial with the second album… [but] if you’re playing to the gallery, you're probably going to lose your soul a bit. So we made a conscious decision to go in the opposite direction.’</p>
<p>Jacob hopes that people will practice ‘active listening’ by giving their undivided attention to Midas during their first playthrough: ‘It’s quite a dark record. [I imagine people listening to it] in a very dark, windowless room with a spring mattress, without the mattress — just the springs.’</p>
<p>Though the initial songwriting ideas for Midas still came from Jacob, he invited his bandmates to write their individual parts around him.</p>
<p>‘I think [Harry, Jamie and Peter] make enough room for what’s important in the basics of the song,’ he explains. ‘Everyone's really good at adding things that I couldn’t think of which don't get in the way of the essence or the sentiment that the song is trying to communicate.’</p>
<p>‘Jacob’s songwriting… all the songs have this space to them. You don't have to force anything,’ Harry adds in agreement. ‘How everyone plays the songs totally informs what I decide to play. These guys give me a creative outlet that just wouldn't exist if I was sitting in my room alone playing guitar.’</p>
<p>Jamie insists that he’s ‘never been part of something with such a strong common goal and a dogged attitude towards what we're trying to achieve,’ adding: ‘I've been in many bands that wanted those things, but have not worked this hard to do it.’</p>
<p>While it was primarily a solo project of Jacob’s, Cub put Wunderhorse firmly among UK guitar music’s brightest prospects. The album placed highly on several best-of lists in 2022 and helped the band earn support slots with the likes of Fontaines D.C., Foals and Sam Fender, as well as a coveted place on the Glastonbury line-up in 2023.</p>
<p>With the band now officially a four-piece and Midas imminent, Wunderhorse’s continued success is the result of the hard yards each bandmember has made over the course of a decade, weaving in and out of other ill-fated bands. This tenacious work ethic should be a priority for young music creators, suggests Jacob.</p>
<p>‘Everything else has to take a back seat if you want to make it work, and I mean everything,’ he tells M. ‘You have to go after it tooth and nail and be prepared to decide that you really want it, especially in the early stages when you're getting yourself established. I’m about to turn 27, it's taken 10 years to get here. These boys are all in the same boat — we've kicked and scratched our way to this point.’</p>
<p>Harry agrees. ‘There's a long period where you're not actually yourself yet, and it takes a long time to get there,’ he says about his own path as a songwriter. ‘But that process can take so long — you have to want it enough. Then it recycles [into] something else later, because you have to catch up with yourself creatively. You find who you are for a brief time, and then you're going to be lost again.’</p>
<p>Peter then jumps in: ‘In the same way that you’ll never finish developing as a person.’</p>
<p>With the band set to embark on their biggest UK and Ireland tour to date in October, including a date at London’s O2 Academy Brixton, the present and future of Wunderhorse look positively upbeat. Though there’s a distinctly humble inter-band aura, Jamie admits one thing about their common goal: ‘I mean, in the back of our minds… it's fucking conquering the world, you know?’</p>
<p>‘Why aim any lower?’ asks Jacob. ‘You can't stop it once you're in this vehicle, and you realise that you can't get off. You might as well see how far it can go. It'll stop when the wheels come off, or it explodes. But up until that point, we're all sitting in it, so let’s take it as far as it can possibly run.’</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.prsformusic.com/m-magazine/features/wunderhorse-interview-2024-midas-jacob-slater" title="29.08.24">Wunderhorse: ‘We’ve kicked and scratched our way to this point’</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】RS: How Wunderhorse became our band of the year]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/RS-interview-4/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/RS-interview-4/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T11:51:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This generational group has weathered change to become one of the UK’s hottest bands. Here, frontman Jacob Slater reflects on the past, and the new music to come</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>This generational group has weathered change to become one of the UK’s hottest bands. Here, frontman Jacob Slater reflects on the past, and the new music to come</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：RollingStone UK
作者：Nick Reilly
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>“I can remember just kind of looking out over the crowd. It’s such a big room and it’s quite dark in there,” recalls Wunderhorse leader Jacob Slater of the band’s sold-out show at Alexandra Palace earlier this year.</p>
<p>“My memory is of scanning the crowd all the way to the back, looking up, and there’s that crazy stained-glass window at the back of the venue. It was still quite bright outside, and you had the last of the light coming through that window and shining down on the crowd. The result was like a weird celestial vision or something. There was something religious about it.”</p>
<p>It’s an apt vision, given that Wunderhorse have spent the past year on the kind of upward trajectory that has left many wondering whether they’re going to become the next great higher power of rock music. An unstoppable 12 months and the tantalising promise of where they could head next are the precise reason why Wunderhorse are worthy winners of The Group Award at the ZYN Rolling Stone UK Awards 2025.</p>
<p>But with an acclaimed second album and sold-out shows under their belt, it might have been difficult for Slater to stop and take stock. “Over the last couple of years, I’ve really learned to try and do a bit more in real time, which helps when you’re trying to take things in,” the singer explains. “I’m not one for talking too much on stage, but the thing that it does is give you a moment to take in what’s actually happening. So that’s what I’ve tried to do over the last year at shows like Glastonbury or Ally Pally. To just breathe for a minute and look at it, so your brain will take a photograph, and you have this visual memory, and it doesn’t become a blur.”</p>
<p>This journey of the past year began in the summer of 2024, when the group released Midas, their incredible second album which we hailed as the sound of a band “that could become generational”. A major part of that record’s appeal was its ability to eschew polished production for something that felt scrappy, raw and genuine. The title track, for instance, was laid down after producer Craig Silvey left the tape running for what the band believed would be a take too unpolished for the final cut. In the end, it was this unfiltered version – recorded in the same Minnesota studio where Nirvana laid down In Utero – that made the grade.</p>
<p>In deciding to take a warts-and-all approach, Wunderhorse have landed on something that evokes the sound of classic guitar bands, all while delivering their own thrilling sound that has put them on a trajectory towards becoming one of the great groups of their own era. It’s all the more remarkable when you consider that in many ways, Midas was the first proper group album and an attempt to move away from the idea that Slater – formerly of the Dead Pretties – had just launched a solo project.</p>
<p>“The first record was under Wunderhorse and was a band record in many ways,” Slater told us last year. “But at the same time, there were these moments where it was just me sitting in a room writing alone, whereas this feels like the first Wunderhorse record as a band. It’s strange in that sense. It feels like us. The last record was a collection of songs from one person, whereas this feels like a time stamp and a really authentic representation of how we were all feeling at the time.”</p>
<p>Twelve months on, there’s the sense that Wunderhorse have become a proper unit during their famously frenetic live shows.</p>
<p>“When you’re playing live every night, people find their space up there and only they can occupy it. Harry [Fowler] guitarist and Jamie [Staples] aren’t just taking up room. The spot they’re standing in is truly theirs, which is a brilliant thing because I wouldn’t want anyone to feel like they were passive and playing along. I want people to feel like they have some ownership of the songs when we’re all playing them together, you know.”</p>
<p>But at the same time, there’s been change afoot. Earlier this year saw the departure of bassist Pete Woodin after seven years, with Seb Byford taking his spot. Slater admits that it could have rocked the boat with big shows looming, but they managed to navigate the chaos as they headed to Ally Pally and later Glastonbury.</p>
<p>“There’s always slight uncertainty with something like that because I’ve known Seb a long time, but there’s the worry that the chemistry might not be there. We were very fortunate because Seb [fitted] right in, and he could step up to the plate right away. Ally Pally was just the third show he played with us. He did really well, and that chemistry continued throughout the year. It’s important nowadays that bands can have that kind of support for each other on the road when things go awry.”</p>
<p>Instead, Byford’s arrival came at the start of a glorious summer. Ally Pally was first, and then a triumphant set on Glastonbury’s Park Stage followed it. It’s worth seeking out footage of that festival set as a reflection of just how revered the band are, especially as a to-capacity crowd scream every word of the anthemic ‘Teal’ from their first album back at them.</p>
<p>“It’s weird, but my memory of Glastonbury is just the smell of the flares,” reflects Slater of the no-pyro-no-party mantra that clearly followed them down on Worthy Farm. “That fireworks-type smell. A lot of people hate it, but the wind was blowing our way, and I just remember the stink of it and all the colours. A lot of people might hate that, but I think it’s nice to see people still using flares. You’d have thought that some boring fuck in the modern age would have outlawed them.” (We’re pretty confident that flares aren’t allowed at Glastonbury, but it certainly speaks volumes of the devotion shown towards this band that a fan was willing to smuggle one in…)</p>
<p>So, what’s next for the winners of The Group Award? Is new music on the horizon?</p>
<p>“I’m just trying to reacquaint myself with some new and different creative processes,” says Slater. “I’ve got some idea of what we’re going to do next, but I’m wary of getting tunnel vision for that too early and blocking out things that might naturally filter in. I’m just off tour and getting back into using my own time in a way that makes me feel sort of stimulated.”</p>
<p>And besides, a hectic touring schedule hasn’t been conducive to writing new material either.</p>
<p>“I wanna be in a space where I can create something again and disappear into a world, which is quite difficult when you’re this weird organism of 16 people that are moving around the world. It’s quite hard to find your own little niche in that, or at least it is for me.”</p>
<p>He adds: “But it is starting to take shape, and I won’t say too much because sometimes you think you know how it’s gonna be and then it turns out totally different. But yeah, there’s definitely the sketch of something coming together, which is good.”</p>
<p>And when it does, we’re of no doubt that the, please forgive us, Midas touch of this special band will come good again…</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://www.rollingstone.co.uk/music/wunderhorse-jacob-slater-interview-photos-56668/" title="2025.12&amp;1 issue">How Wunderhorse became our band of the year</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】MARVIN x Wunderhorse: Jacob Slater isn’t Jockeying for Attention]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/marvin-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/marvin-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T11:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Marvin magazine</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with Marvin magazine</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：Marvin
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>It’s no wonder that Jacob Slater is sounding a wee bit hoarse; his band Wunderhorse have just roared across the USA for their first stateside headline tour. “I got a bit sick in the middle, which was a bit shit. I didn’t want to cancel shows but I got laryngitis and I couldn’t fucking sing a note anyway,” he says, with a slight rasp, over Zoom. The doctor that Slater saw advised him not to perform. “He didn’t give me anything. But they have this thing in America called Throat Coat tea, so he said just drink loads of Throat Coat.”<br>
Is it a little like Lemsip, the UK’s premier lemon-flavoured cold-and-flu panacea? “It’s like Lemsip on steroids,” he says, sacrificing his strung-out vocal cords to imitate an American accent. “Bigger and bettttter!”</p>
<p>Just like Wunderhorse, then. In under three years, Slater’s band have gone from Shetland pony to Shire stallion, if you will. After releasing their debut album Cub in 2022, the London band rapidly notched up supporting slots for the likes of Fontaines D.C., Pixies and – it writes itself, doesn’t it – Foals.</p>
<p>Then, came Midas, released last summer; a Bildungsroman of teenage romance told through grungy hooks, loud-quiet song structures, and belt-it-out choruses. And the latest US tour, swollen voice box aside, was a knockout; it saw the group travel coast to coast, headlining legendary venues including NYC’s Bowery Ballroom and LA’s Troubadour.</p>
<p>Before Wunderhorse, Slater was the frontman of the Dead Pretties, a snarling indie outfit that would have been the kings of Camden had they come around a decade prior to their 2016 inception. “There was a youthful naivety that’s necessary to undertake something as silly as starting a band,” he says. They built up a cult following in the UK capital — and Wunderhorse’s latest stuff undoubtedly riffs off the gnarly guitars — but the group disbanded within a year, leaving behind a prophetic note on their Instagram: “You will undoubtedly see us playing in new bands and under new names in the near future,” it read. I remind Slater. “It’s what I love to do and what I do best,” Slater says. “Why the hell would I do anything else?”</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768476817102.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Slater took a time out and went back home to Newquay, a coastal town in Cornwall, to teach surfing. He also landed an acting role in Pistol — Danny Boyle’s 2022 TV drama about The Sex Pistols — as drummer Paul Cook. He played a solid sticksman, but he didn’t enjoy the glitz and glamour that came with appearing in a major series. “The whole red carpet celebrity thing…it’s total horseshit,” he says.</p>
<p>Slater began work on Wunderhorse as a solo project, named after Champion the Wonder Horse, a rooting-tooting, kids’ Western series from the ‘50s (regrettably, Slater didn’t get a chance to visit the statue of the stallion, in LA’s Museum of the American West, while stateside). He quickly got interest from labels; but he wanted a full herd to flesh out the songs. Joining forces with Oscar Browne (guitar, now left); Harry Tristan Fowler (guitar); Peter Woodin (bass); and Jamie Staples (drums), the newly-formed band released debut album Cub in October 2022.</p>
<p>The record is achingly vital, a vial of youth seen through sex and drugs and, obviously, fucking good rock and roll. And those gritty, raspy, growling vocals; Slater uses his voice percussively, wringing the meaning out of every single word, hitting your eardrums until it reverberates in your brain. The album’s lead single “Teal” captures the hazy wanderlust of being a teenager, when “nothing was real man, you know what I mean.” It’s a hazy, filmic snapshot of a pulsating summer which took them on the road alongside the likes of Sam Fender and Fontaines.</p>
<p>In 2023, Wunderhorse recorded their second album at the legendary Pachyderm Studio in Minnesota (where Nirvana’s In Utero was birthed) in just three weeks. “I’m not into that hippy-dippy kind of thing but some places seem to welcome in the muse or whatever you call it and Pachyderm is really like that. You enter a different state of mind,” he says. Boldly, the band pretty much wrote the entire LP while there. “We didn’t tell anyone we were doing that until afterwards,” he laughs. “Sometimes you’ve gotta roll the dice.”</p>
<p>On the matter of tumbling dice, it was Rolling Stones producer Craig Silvey who steered the band towards a sense of organised chaos, resulting in a neat, undiluted, heady spirit that runs throughout every track. The key was creating genuine imperfection; like wearing-in a pair of jeans properly rather than emptying your pockets for some “distressed” raw denim bullshit. “You can’t think about it too much. [Otherwise] you have a meltdown and move to a trailer park and fucking start working at Aqua Splash to try to refocus. I’ve thought about it.”</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="2"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768476928384.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Waterpark existential crises aside, the band is gearing up to headline  legendary London venue Alexandra Palace for their biggest headline show to date this May 29. “We’re all stoked,” he says. Will they use the Champion the Wonder Horse theme tune for their walk-on song? “It’s a contender,” Slater says. Either way, the gig is set to bring together 10,000 Wunderhorse fans, all under one roof rocking.</p>
<p>For Slater, this is still what it’s all about. “That’s the whole point. The fans who skip school or get the train to the gig and are young and their eyes are lit up, it gives you hope,” he says. “Maybe that element of the human spirit isn’t dead yet. And it really matters to me. It’s one of the most important things in the world,” he says. It beats feeding the content machine any day. “I try to stay as true to myself as possible. I don’t make them but you know there are TikTok videos of you out there. I’m becoming a bit of an old man. But it is odd,” he says.</p>
<p>I tell Slater that one fan on Wunderhorse’s Subreddit (I have to explain what this is) is obsessed with trying to find out the exact model of sneakers he wears. He laughs; it turns out Slater’s tour Vans aren’t as coveted as they might seem. “I don’t know. They’re just black. They were the cheapest ones. They finally died a death in Liverpool, so I think they’re in a bin there if he wants to go and find them.” Cue a Merseyside rummage for one zealous fan.</p>
<p>Could there be a commercial partnership with Vans down the line? “Who knows! You hear a lot about sponsorships and they kind of rarely happen.” Fair play. But based on Wunderhorse inevitably getting even bigger and better, maybe, just maybe, I’m speaking to the future voice of Throat Coat.</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://marvin.la/marvin-x-wunderhorse-jacob-slater-isnt-jockeying-for-attention/?fbclid=PAZXh0bgNhZW0CMTEAAacPsazCXJrJsdIowbD49OygATRzbBOnb_kswATraJk-AusHLcqdPM5Tlc_HvA_aem__jcnSvZbJSgT7EsEXgL4TA" title="2025">MARVIN x Wunderhorse: Jacob Slater isn’t Jockeying for Attention</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[【采访】Wunderhorse catches up with an old friend]]></title>
        <id>https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/the-rodeo-interview-1/</id>
        <link href="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post/the-rodeo-interview-1/">
        </link>
        <updated>2026-01-15T10:54:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with an old friend.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>A talk with an old friend.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- more -->
<pre><code>原载于：The Rodeo
作者：Jessie Smith
</code></pre>
<hr>
<p>No one had warned Jacob Slater of Wunderhorse that I would be the one interviewing him, and having known him for six years it was a joy to hear him cry out ‘NO WAY’ as I appeared before him on Zoom. Having also been a part of his foray into acting whilst on the set of Danny Boyle’s Pistol (launching via Disney+ on May 31st), as well as having witnessed the rise and fall of Dead Pretties, I took the opportunity to catch up with Jacob and reminisce about our ‘not-so-long-ago-or-far-away’ youth.</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768475763365.jpeg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p><strong>Jessie: How are you Jacob?</strong></p>
<p>Jacob: I’m actually a bit ill to be honest.</p>
<p><strong>COVID or just run down?</strong></p>
<p>Just got a sniffly nose and a sore throat. But it’s fine. I’ve got a mug with a picture of a trout on it so everything is going to be okay.</p>
<p><strong>I’ve got a mug that says ‘21: ADULTING IS MY SUPERPOWER’ on it, so we’re both doing really well.</strong></p>
<p>Nice, that’s cool.</p>
<p><strong>So, first of all I don’t feel like I can do a formal Q&amp;A with you, that would be very strange. I have some bullet points of things I want answers to, but we’re just going to have a chat.</strong></p>
<p>Go for it, Jessie.</p>
<p><strong>Alright, so who are we hearing play alongside you on ‘Butterflies’?</strong></p>
<p>That would be me, Pete Woodin and Jamie Staples. Oscar Browne is on the recordings but has since left to do his own thing. Now we have Harry Fowler, an old school friend of mine, which is great – ten years ago we were bunking off school and now we’re here. Pete used to go to the school just up the road from ours, and he was in Harry’s band when we were kids.</p>
<p><strong>So it’s properly full circle.</strong></p>
<p>Exactly, it feels good.</p>
<p><strong>It’s funny to me that so many of Wunderhorse’s songs touch on the past and nostalgia, because in a weird way you are a kind of vessel for my own nostalgia.</strong></p>
<p>I get that.</p>
<p>**You are so tied in with a very formative section of my life, in a way you and Dead Pretties were a soundtrack to it. I was even there on that tour in 2017, with my ex-boyfriend and I in your van – **</p>
<p>I remember that. Well, I remember the first half of that tour, I don’t really remember the second half.</p>
<p><strong>No, I don’t remember how we got back to London. One minute we were in Southampton and then suddenly it was the next morning and I was waking up on one of the sofas in your living room.</strong></p>
<p>I don’t even remember Southampton. I didn’t know we’d played Southampton till a couple of weeks later when pictures emerged.</p>
<p><img src="https://requiemvaccaro.github.io/post-images/1768475891632.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
(Jacob Slater on tour with Dead Pretties, c. 2017)</p>
<p><strong>What do you reckon has changed for you, musically, in the four years since then?</strong></p>
<p>The music that we made had a blueprint that only fit a certain type, and it didn’t feel like a good vehicle for the other types of music I wanted to do. I just feel like it wouldn’t have worked given the reputation that we’d built up for ourselves. If I’d have been like ‘Oh! Now I’m going to do an introspective acoustic ballad’…</p>
<p><strong>It wouldn’t have quite fit in with ‘Social Experiment’ and ‘Confidence’.</strong></p>
<p>Exactly, yeah. I think if you’re going to make that kind of music, 17 to 20 is a good time to get it out of you, you know? Get all that anger and the confusion of being a young person out. All the ‘THIS IS WHAT I WANT AND THIS IS WHAT I HAVE TO SAY’ will always wind up being questioned in the end. Lots of musical artists’ first endeavours are them just finding their feet.</p>
<p><strong>Back to ‘Butterflies’, you say it’s looking at your teenage self through the lens of your adult self. What advice would you give teenage Jacob now?</strong></p>
<p>I’d definitely say to watch out for all ‘the stuff that goes along with the music’. It always starts off as being ‘the stuff that goes along with the music’, and then it turns into the stuff that goes along with the music becomes the music, and then it comes before the music – If you want a really inarticulate way of saying that.</p>
<p><strong>In a way it’s good to figure that out by 24, even though it’s hard to go through it all so young. At least you have it figured out by 24 rather than 34, 44, etcetera. It’s not your whole life.</strong></p>
<p>It definitely gets a lot of people. I don’t know why those themes seem to have to always come with so many of the creative industries but they do. It always starts off as ‘serving the muse’, then it enslaves you and that ‘muse’ disappears after a while.</p>
<p><strong>You’re left doing more because you’re chasing that feeling, you want to get the ‘muse’ back.</strong></p>
<p>When I was young I just thought that being crazy was what I was supposed to do, and you kind of push the limits, you know?</p>
<p><strong>How does it feel getting back into performing live post-pandemic?</strong></p>
<p>It feels good! At first it was odd, it was the longest period I’ve ever gone since I was 13 without playing a live show. I’ve always played in pubs or whatever, done bits and bobs. So when I got back up there, I kind of had a semi-out-of-body experience where I could almost see myself doing it, and it felt strange. But after the first couple of shows we properly got back into it and got into our stride. If you play good shows with a responsive audience it’s always going to help you settle back into remembering that this is what you want to do.</p>
<p><strong>Of course last year you had a very different experience when it comes to performing, doing Pistol. How did you feel when that first teaser trailer came out?</strong></p>
<p>I felt okay because I wasn’t really in it.</p>
<p><strong>I was! Did you see me?</strong></p>
<p>Yeah yeah! I was like ‘Jessie’s in it, I’m not fucking in it.’</p>
<p><strong>One of my favourite memories from filming – I’m not even sure how much I can talk about this because Disney might hurt me – is that there was this one moment where Danny (Boyle) gave you a bit of creative control when directing a scene. Were there any more moments like that?</strong></p>
<p>There were points where musically maybe a bit of trust was put in me, because after a few months of doing it they worked out that I could hold a band together, just about. This show was unique because we weren’t miming, we were playing live, and that can raise some technical problems sometimes. You have to be flexible and able to adapt to the scene you were doing. I’m not taking credit for it because there was a whole team behind the musical arrangements, but there were times where I’d be involved in trying to work out how we fit the scene around the music or visa versa. I remember the scene you’re talking about really well.</p>
<p><strong>I felt like a proud mum.</strong></p>
<p>It was great. It’s obviously my first acting job and it was great I could bring something to the table that others weren’t as experienced in. It was all totally new to me, and I was learning from everyone around me, but it was nice to bring something of my own ilk.</p>
<p><strong>How was the process of becoming Paul Cook? I know that many of the real people got very much involved in the process, apart from one glaring omission (John Lydon), did you get to speak with Cook at all?</strong></p>
<p>I got to meet the man, and he was wonderful, a true gent. I know he has stories, I know he has stories, but he’s kind of understated guy and not reserved in a cold way. He carried himself in such a ‘guy-next-door’ way for someone who’d been a part of such a massive movement, there was no ego, he was sure of himself and who he was. It was wonderful to be around, he was accommodating and very helpful with the drumming. A true gent, tough to read sometimes, but it was just wonderful to meet him and observe him without being too invasive.</p>
<p><strong>One of my other favourite memories was the first day I appeared on set. You found out I was there and must have bolted in my direction, because one minute there was no one standing next to me and the next minute you were just there and you immediately swept me up into one of the biggest hugs I’d had in years.</strong></p>
<p>I was just really stoked to see you, it was such a nice surprise. I think it was just so nice to see a face from my world, because I was spending every day in this thing where I felt so out of my depth. It was something to cling onto.</p>
<hr>
<p>原文链接：<a href="https://therodeomag.com/2022/04/30/wunderhorse-catches-up-with-an-old-friend/" title="30.04.22">Wunderhorse catches up with an old friend</a></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>